Seoul, Republic of Korea

🛘 (+82) 10-3125-7712 | 🗷 achromatically@naver.com | 🏕 shinhyeokoh.github.io | 🗖 shinhyeok-oh-5082b51a8 | 📂 Google Scholar

## **Summary**

I obtained a master's degree in computer and communications engineering from the Kangwon National University, under the guidance of Prof. Harksoo Kim. I am currently working at Riiid as Research Scientist (NLP). I enjoy discussing topics related to transfer learning. I find pleasure in exploring ways, such as self-supervised learning, domain adaptation, and multimodality, to extract value from previously unutilized something.

## **Education**

#### **Kangwon National University**

M.S. IN DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING, GPA 4.31 / 4.5

Chuncheon, Republic of Korea

Sep 2019 - Feb 2021

Mar 2016 - Feb 2021

#### **Kangwon National University**

B.S. IN DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING, GPA 3.86 / 4.5

Chuncheon, Republic of Korea

## **Experience**

Riiid Seoul, Republic of Korea

Dec 2022 - Present

Apr 2021 - Dec 2022

Sep 2020 - Feb 2021

Mar 2020 - Sep 2020

Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

NLP RESEARCH SCIENTIST

- Research on Large Language Model
- · Research on Automatic Essay Assessment
- Research on Question Generation & Evaluation
- · Data Analysis and Qualification for Procured Data

**Netmarble** Seoul, Republic of Korea

NLP RESEARCHER & ENGINEER

- · Maintenance on Game NMT Service
- Research on Automatic Post-editing
- Research on Text-to-Speech Synthesis
- Development of Persona Chatbot
- Development of Chatbot with Passage Retrieval

Kakao Enterprise Seongnam, Republic of Korea

NLP RESEARCHER (RESEARCH INTERNSHIP)

Research on Aspect-based Sentiment Analysis using Self-supervised and Multi-task Learning

**NLP Lab - Konkuk University** Seoul, Republic of Korea

STUDENT (ADVISOR: PROF. HARKSOO KIM)

· Research on Persona-based Chatbot

Development of Korean Language Model

**NLP Lab - Kangwon National University** Chuncheon, Republic of Korea

STUDENT (ADVISOR: PROF. HARKSOO KIM) · Research on Persona-based Chatbot

Self-employed - Kmong Republic of Korea

DEVELOPER

· Development of Web, Android, Application Software

• 30+ Projects

## **Publications**

#### INTERNATIONAL PUBLICATIONS

#### **Multi-Architecture Multi-Expert Diffusion Models**

Yunsung Lee\*, Jin-Young Kim\*, Hyojun Go\*, Myeongho Jeong, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Seungtaek Choi

Arxiv Preprint (Under review)

(\*co-first author)

#### **Addressing Negative Transfer in Diffusion Models**

Hyojun Go\*, JinYoung Kim\*, Yunsung Lee\*, Seunghyun Lee, Shinhyeok Oh, Hyeongdon Moon, Seungtaek Choi

(\*co-first author)

NeurIPS 2023 (Accepted)

#### **Evaluation of Question Generation Needs More References**

<u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>\*, Hyojun Go\*, Hyeongdon Moon, Yunsung Lee, Myeongho Jeong, Hyun Seung Lee and Seungtaek Choi

ACL 2023 (Findings, short)

(\*equal contribution)

#### **Cross Encoding As Augmentation: Towards Effective Educational Text Classification**

Hyun Seung Lee\*, Seungtaek Choi\*, Yunsung Lee, Hyeongdon Moon, Shinhyeok Oh, Myeongho Jeong, Hyojun Go, Christian

Wallraven

(\*equal contribution)

ACL 2023 (Findings, short)

# RWEN-TTS: Relation-aware Word Encoding Network for Natural Text-to-Speech Synthesis

Shinhyeok Oh\*, HyeongRae Noh\*, Yoonseok Hong, Insoo Oh

(\*equal contribution)

AAAI 2023 (Oral Presentation)

#### Netmarble AI Center's WMT21 Automatic Post-Editing Shared Task Submission

<u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>\*, Sion Jang\*, Hu Xu\*, Shounan An, Insoo Oh (\*equal contribution)

WMT @EMNLP 2021 (1st place)

### Deep Context- and Relation-Aware Learning for Aspect-based Sentiment Analysis

Shinhyeok Oh\*, Dongyub Lee\*, Taesun Whang, IlNam Park, Gaeun Seo, EungGyun Kim, Harksoo Kim (\*equal contribution)

ACL 2021 (Oral Presentation, short)

#### Improving Document-Level Sentiment Classification Using Importance of Sentences

Gihyeon Choi, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Harksoo Kim

Entropy, 2020 (SCIE)

## Multi-Turn Chatbot Based on Query-Context Attentions and Dual Wasserstein Generative Adversarial Networks

Jintae Kim, <u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>, Oh-Woog Kwon, Harksoo Kim Appl. Sci., 2019 (SCIE)

#### **DOMESTIC PUBLICATIONS**

#### **Method of Reflecting Various Personas in a Chatbot**

Shinhyeok Oh, Seokwon Jung, Harksoo Kim

Journal of KIISE, 2021 (KCI)

### Movie Revies Sentiment Analysis Considering the Order in which Sentiment Words Appear

 $\textit{HongJin Kim, Damrin Kim, Boeun Kim, } \underline{\textit{Shinhyeok Oh}}, \textit{Harksoo Kim}$ 

HCLT 2020

#### **Korean Named Entity Recognition Using ELECTRA and Label Attention Network**

HongJin Kim, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2020

#### **Korean Generative Chatbot using Topic Embedding**

Shinhyeok Oh, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2020

#### **Personal Characteristics Classifier for Persona Chatbot Research**

<u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>, Harksoo Kim, Jeong-Eom Lee, Seona Kim, Youngmin Park, Myungho Noh

KSC 2019

#### Personalized Multi-Turn Chatbot Based on Dual WGAN

<u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>, Jintae Kim, Harksoo Kim, Jeong-Eom Lee, Seona Kim, Youngmin Park, Myungho Noh

HCLT 2019

#### Multi-head Attention and Pointer Network Based Syllables Dependency Parser

HongJin Kim, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Damrin Kim, Boeun Kim, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2019

#### **Persona Reflection Method for Generative Chatbot System**

Shinhyeok Oh, Jintae Kim, Youngmin Park, Seona Kim, Jeong-Eom Lee, Harksoo Kim

KCC 2019

#### **Korean Dependency Parsing Using ELMo and Multi-head Attention**

Seongsik Park, Shinhyeok Oh, Hongjin Kim, Sihyung Kim, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2018

#### Korean Dependency Parsing using Multi-head Attention and Pointer Network

Seongsik Park, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Hongjin Kim, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2018

## **Honors & Awards**

Nov 2021 1st Place, Automatic Post-Editing shared task @WMT, EMNLP 2021

Oct 2020 Special Prize, Korean Language Information Processing Competition - Chatbot @HCLT 2020

Oct 2020 Special Prize, Korean Language Information Processing Competition - Sentiment Analysis @HCLT 2020

Oct 2019 Bronze Prize, Korean Language Information Processing Competition - Dependency Parsing @HCLT 2019

Sep 2019 Gold Prize, Kangwon SW Festival - @National Program of Excellence in Software

Oct 2018 Grand Prize, Korean Language Information Processing Competition - Dependency Parsing @HCLT 2019

Jul 2016 1st Place, Department of Computer and Communications Engineering (Rank: 1/97), Spring Semester 2016

## Certificate

#### **Certificate of Engineer Information Processing**

HUMAN RESOURCES DEVELOPMENT SERVICE OF KOREA

Republic of Korea

2019

## Skills

- Languages: Python, Java, C, C#, HTML/CSS/JS, Android
- · Deep Learning Libs: PyTorch, Tensorflow
- Etc.: Springboot, Gnuboard, Google Cloud Platform

## **Teaching Experience**

2023	Instructor,	Special Lecture for Freshm	an (AI Foundation Models)	@Kangwon National University
------	-------------	----------------------------	---------------------------	------------------------------

2022 Instructor, Special Lecture for Junior (Career in Artificial Intelligence) @Kangwon National University

2020 **Teaching Assistant**, Natural Language Processing @LG Uplus

2018-2019 **Teaching Assistant**, Java Programming, C Programming, App Programing @Kangwon National University

2017 **Instructor**, Java Programming (Supplementary classes supported by Kangwon National University)

Republic of Korea Republic of Korea Republic of Korea Republic of Korea Republic of Korea

## **Academic Activities**

- Reviewer of ACL, NAACL, EACL, and ARR
- Reviewer of IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing